Sync & corrections by Blue-Bird™
Provided by explosiveskull
(https://twitter.com/kaboomskull)
Srt2smi by Blue-Bird™
I got nothing, sir.
No sign of Niobe or Ghost.
Nothing but blue pills.
Should we try to contact them?
Won't matter.
My gut says they're down.
- We should start back.
- If that ship can fly, we need it.
I was afraid you'd say that.
Search every pipe, every hole,
every crack we know.
Sweep as wide as possible,
as fast as possible.
- Lines are crawling with calamari.
- Then the sooner we find them the better.
Thought you could use
something to eat.
Thank you.
Any change?
No.
- How is he?
- He's gonna be fine.
At least until he wakes up.
- What do you mean?
- Captain has some questions for him.
He'd better have some good answers.
You see these cuts?
I think they're self-inflicted.
- Why?
- VDTs maybe. I don't know.
But like I said,
the answer better be good.
Roland, I'd like to run
another search through the Matrix.
- For what?
- For Neo.
How could he be in the Matrix, sir?
He's not plugged in.
Please, for me.
This is what keeps bothering me.
What?
His neural patterns don't read
like someone who's in a coma.
The strange thing is,
I see these patterns all the time.
- Where?
- On someone jacked in.
The big bupkes. Nada.
He's not in there.
- Sir, I got the projections.
- How long?
Based on point of entry and past speed,
the machines will be in Zion in 20 hours.
Jesus H. Christ.
All right, let's move with a purpose.
AK, I want you on holographics.
Mauser, I want forward and aft guns
manned at all times.
Make sure we're running
on as few pads as possible.
- Yes, sir.
- Hey.
- Hey! You got a call.
- What?
Operator.
It's Seraph.
I bring word from the Oracle.
You must come at once.
Good morning.
- Who are you?
- My name is Sati. Your name is Neo.
My papa says you're not supposed
to be here. He says you must be lost.
Are you lost, Neo?
- Where am I?
- This is the train station.
- This isn't the Matrix?
- That's where the train goes.
That's where we're going,
but you cannot go with us.
- Why not?
- He won't let you.
- Who won't?
- The Trainman. I don't like him.
But my papa says we have to do
what the Trainman says...
...or else he will leave us here
forever and ever.
Morpheus, Trinity,
thank you for coming.
One thing I've learned in all my years...
...is that nothing ever works out
the way you want it to.
- Who are you?
- I'm the Oracle.
I wish there was an easy way to get
through this, but there ain't.
I'm sorry this had to happen.
I'm sorry I couldn't be sitting here
like you remember me...
- ...but it wasn't meant to be.
- What happened?
I made a choice, and that choice
cost me more than I wanted it to.
What choice?
To help you, to guide Neo.
Now, since the real test for any choice is
having to make the same choice again...
...knowing full well
what it might cost...
...I guess I feel pretty good
about that choice...
...because here I am, at it again.
- Do you know what happened to Neo?
- Yes.
He is trapped in a place between
this world and the machine world.
The link is controlled by a program
called the Trainman.
He uses it to smuggle programs
in and out of the Matrix.
If he finds out where Neo is
before you get to him...
...then I'm afraid our choices
are going to become difficult.
- Why?
- Because of who the Trainman works for.
The Merovingian.
He has placed a bounty on your lives.
You must be careful at all times.
Seraph knows how to find the Trainman.
He'll go with you.
For years he has protected me.
I hope he can do the same for you.
Please, follow me.
Oracle....
I know, Morpheus.
I can see you're filled with doubt,
clouded by uncertainty.
After everything that has happened,
how can you expect me to believe you?
I don't.
I expect just what I've always expected:
For you to make up your own
damn mind. Believe me or don't.
All I can do is tell you that your friend
is in trouble, and he needs your help.
He needs all our help.
- Are you from the Matrix?
- Yes.
No.
- I mean, I was.
- Why did you leave?
- I had to.
- I had to leave my home too.
Sati! Come here, darling.
Leave the poor man in peace.
Yes, Papa.
I am sorry. She is still very curious.
- I know you.
- Yes, in the restaurant of the Frenchman.
I am Rama-Kandra. This is my wife,
Kamala. My daughter, Sati.
We are most honored to meet you.
- You are programs.
- Oh, yes.
I am the power-plant systems manager
for recycling operations.
My wife is an interactive software
programmer. She is highly creative.
What are you doing here?
You do not belong here.
Kamala! Goodness, I apologize.
My wife can be very direct.
It's okay.
I don't have an answer.
- I don't even know where "here" is.
- This place is nowhere.
It is between your world and our world.
- Who's the Trainman?
- He works for the Frenchman.
Why did I know
you were going to say that?
The Frenchman does not forget,
and he does not forgive.
- You know him?
- I know only what I need to know.
I know if you want to take something
from our world into your world...
...that does not belong there,
you must go to the Frenchman.
Is that what you're doing here?
- Rama, please.
- I do not want to be cruel, Kamala.
He may never see another face
for the rest of his life.
I'm sorry.
- You don't have to answer that question.
- No, I don't mind.
The answer is simple.
I love my daughter very much.
I find her to be the most beautiful thing
I have ever seen.
But where we are from,
that is not enough.
Every program that is created
must have a purpose.
If it does not, it is deleted.
I went to the Frenchman
to save my daughter.
- You do not understand.
- I just have never--
Heard a program speak of love.
- It is a human emotion.
- No, it is a word.
What matters is the connection
the word implies.
I see that you are in love.
Can you tell me what you would give
to hold on to that connection?
Anything.
Then perhaps the reason you are here...
...is not so different
than the reason I am here.
That's him.
- Get away! Get away from me!
- We don't want trouble.
- Get the hell away from me!
- We need your help.
I can't help you!
No one can help you!
Oh, no!
Damn it!
- When is the train due?
- It is already late.
It's not like the Trainman to be late.
You think it has something
to do with me?
I cannot say.
Who knows such things?
Only the Oracle.
- You know the Oracle?
- Everyone knows the Oracle.
I consulted with her
before I met with the Frenchman.
She promised she'd look after Sati
after we said goodbye.
Goodbye?
- You're not staying with her?
- It is not possible.
Our arrangement with the Frenchman
was for our daughter only.
- My wife and I must return to our world.
- Why?
- That is our karma.
- You believe in karma?
Karma is a word, like love.
A way of saying:
"What I am here to do."
I do not resent my karma.
I'm grateful for it.
Grateful for my wonderful wife,
for my beautiful daughter.
They are gifts, and so I do
what I must do to honor them.
- Papa, the train!
- Yes. Find your bag. Quickly.
Can I carry that for you?
All right.
Hurry it up, I'm late!
Who are you?
- He is a friend.
- Rama!
I know you.
- So that's what they wanted.
- I need to get back.
- I'll pay you whatever you want.
- Oh.
One way or another,
I'm getting on this train.
Oh, no, no, no.
You'll stay right here until
the Merovingian says different.
If I know him...
...you're gonna be here
for a long, long time.
- I don't want to hurt you.
- You don't get it.
I built this place.
Down here, I make the rules.
Down here, I make the threats.
Down here, I'm God.
Get on the train
or you'll stay here with him.
We should return to the Oracle.
She will know what to do.
No. We know what has to be done.
Shit.
You gotta be kidding.
Holy shit, it's wingless.
I get it.
You must be ready to die.
I need to speak with him.
Only way you're getting through
this door is over my big, dead ass.
So be it.
There are no weapons allowed
in the club.
At the bottom of this elevator,
there is a coat-check girl...
...and if we are lucky,
one man for checking weapons.
And if we're unlucky?
There will be many men.
Can I take your--? Oh, my God.
What in the hell?
I don't believe this.
Hey! Hey!
The prodigal child returns.
Are you here for the bounty, Seraph?
Tell me, how many bullets
are there in those guns?
I don't know, but I don't think
you have enough.
- We only want to talk.
- Oh, yes.
I'm sure you do. You have fought
through Hel to do so. Yes?
I'll tell you what I will do.
Put down the guns, and I will promise
you a safe passage out of here.
- All three of us?
- Oh, yes, yes.
Of course.
Who could have guessed we'd see each
other so soon after our last meeting?
The Fates are too kind, eh?
And since you, my little Judas,
have brought them here...
...I can only surmise the fortuneteller
has found herself another shell?
Disappointing, but not unexpected.
I do hope, however, she has the good
manners to learn her lesson...
...and to remember that there is
no action without consequence.
And if you take something from me,
you will pay the price.
You know why we are here?
Come now, what kind of question
is this? Of course I know.
It is my business to know.
Some might think this is a strange
coincidence, but I do not.
I am curious, though,
as to how it actually happened.
- Do you know?
- No.
No?
I did not think so.
But it is always best to ask, huh?
We want to make a deal.
Always straight to business,
huh, Morpheus?
Okay. I have something you want.
To make a deal...
...you must have something
I want, yes?
And it so happens
there is something I want.
Something I have wanted
ever since I first came here.
It is said they cannot be taken...
...they can only be given.
What?
The eyes of the Oracle.
I told you before, there is no escaping
the nature of the universe.
It is that nature
that has again brought you to me.
Where some see coincidence,
I see consequence.
Where others see chance...
...I see cost.
Bring me the eyes of the Oracle...
...and I will give you back your savior.
It seems a perfectly fair
and reasonable deal to me.
Yes? No?
I don't have time for this shit.
You wanna make a deal?
How about this?
You give me Neo, or we all die,
right here, right now.
Interesting deal.
You are really ready to die
for this man?
- Believe it.
- She'll do it.
If she has to,
she'll kill every one of us.
She's in love.
It is remarkable how similar the pattern
of love is to the pattern of insanity.
Time's up.
What's it gonna be, Merv?
Okay. You got yourself in here...
...you can get yourself out.
Are you ready for us?
Almost, sir. They got
some pretty ancient hacks here.
- But you found Neo?
- Can't you see him?
No, sir. We were reading something,
but I couldn't tell what.
I can't leave yet.
I have to see her.
Now?
It's my last chance.
That's it. That's the secret.
- You've got to use your hands.
- Why?
Cookies need love like everything does.
Neo!
I was hoping to have these done
before you got here. Oh, well.
Sati, honey, I think it's time
for a tasting.
Take the bowl to Seraph
and find out if they're ready.
Okay.
- I'm glad you got out.
- Me too.
So do you recognize me?
- A part of you.
- Yeah, that's how it works.
Some bits you lose,
some bits you keep.
I don't yet recognize my face
in the mirror...
...but I still love candy.
No, thank you.
Remember what you were like
when you first walked through my door?
Jittery as a June bug.
And now, just look at you.
You sure did surprise me, Neo,
and you still do.
You gave me a few surprises too.
I hope I helped.
You helped me to get here,
but my question is, why?
Where is this going?
- Where does it end?
- I don't know.
- You don't know or you won't tell me?
- I told you before...
...no one can see beyond a choice they
don't understand, and I mean no one.
- What choice?
- It doesn't matter. It's my choice.
I have mine to make,
same as you have yours.
Does that include what things
to tell me and what not to?
Of course not.
Then why didn't you tell me
about the Architect?
About Zion and the ones before me?
Why didn't you tell me the truth?
- Because it wasn't time for you to know.
- Who decided it wasn't time?
You know who.
I did.
Then I think it's time for me to know
a few more things.
So do I.
Tell me how I separated my mind
from my body without jacking in.
Tell me how I stopped four sentinels
by thinking it.
Tell me just what the hell
is happening to me.
The power of the One
extends beyond this world.
It reaches from here all the way back
to where it came from.
- Where?
- The source.
That's what you felt when you touched
those sentinels, but you weren't ready.
You should be dead, but apparently
you weren't ready for that either.
The Architect told me that
if I didn't return to the source...
...Zion would be destroyed tonight.
Please. You and I may not be able
to see beyond our own choices...
...but that man can't see
past any choice.
- Why not?
- He doesn't understand them. He can't.
To him, they are variables
in an equation.
One at a time, each variable
must be solved, then countered.
That's his purpose.
To balance the equation.
What's your purpose?
To unbalance it.
Why? What do you want?
I want the same thing you want, Neo.
And I'm willing to go
as far as you are to get it.
The end of the war.
Is it going to end?
One way or another.
Can Zion be saved?
I'm sorry, I don't have the answer
to that question, but....
If there is an answer, there's only
one place you're going to find it.
- Where?
- You know where.
And if you can't find the answer...
...then I'm afraid there may be
no tomorrow for any of us.
What does that mean?
Everything that has a beginning...
...has an end.
I see the end coming.
I see the darkness spreading.
I see death.
And you are all that stands in his way.
Smith.
Very soon, he is going to have the power
to destroy this world.
But I believe he won't stop there.
He can't.
He won't stop until
there's nothing left at all.
What is he?
He is you.
Your opposite, your negative.
The result of the equation
trying to balance itself out.
- And if I can't stop him?
- One way or another, Neo...
...this war is going to end.
Tonight, the future of both worlds
will be in your hands...
...or in his.
How are you feeling?
Are you all right?
I need time.
- That figures.
- Captain Roland.
- What's up, Maggie?
- Bane is. He's conscious.
Good. Maybe he's got some answers.
Mm!
I love that smell.
I sure am going to miss it.
- Oracle.
- I know.
I know.
Sati, honey.
Take a few cookies and go with Seraph.
Can I come back?
I would like to come back.
- I would like that too.
- Then I'll see you tomorrow.
I hope so, hon, I hope so.
I'm scared, Seraph.
Come.
He's following us.
Well, well, it's been a long time.
I remember chasing you
was like chasing a ghost.
I have beaten you before.
Yes, true, but as you can see,
things are a little different now.
And you must be the last exile.
- The Oracle told me about you.
- Really?
What did she say about me?
That you were a bad man.
Oh, I'm not so bad,
once you get to know me.
The great and powerful Oracle,
we meet at last.
I suppose you've been
expecting me, right?
The all-knowing Oracle
is never surprised.
How can she be? She knows everything.
But if that's true, then why is she here
if she knew I was coming?
Why wouldn't she leave?
Maybe you knew I would do that,
maybe you didn't.
If you did, that means you baked those
cookies and set that plate there...
...deliberately, purposefully...
...which means that you're sitting there
also deliberately, purposefully.
What did you do with Sati?
"Cookies need love
like everything does."
You are a bastard.
You would know, Mom.
Do what you're here to do.
Yes, ma'am.
I really wish I could help, but I just....
I don't remember any of it.
What about the cuts on your arms?
Those cuts are more than one day old.
Yeah, definitely.
You're right about that, sir.
They look like they
might be self-inflicted.
But why would I do something
like that to myself?
Unless, of course, I wasn't myself.
But if I'm not me, then who am I?
- Has this man been tested for VDTs?
- Yes, sir. It was negative.
But he is showing a lot
of unusual neural activity.
Some cross-synaptic firing,
as well as signs of recent trauma...
...with fresh fibrotic scarring
throughout the cortex.
I want the truth. I don't care
what it takes. Make him remember.
Sir, we found her.
- The Logos?
- Yes, sir.
About time we had
some goddamn good news.
Are the thermals picking up
any signs of life?
No, sir. Nothing yet.
- What about the ship?
- Holographic says the hull's intact.
- Drop down and keep a man in the turret.
- Yes, sir.
Get a full diagnostic on that ship
as fast as humanly possible.
Careful, sir.
The squids are sneaky bastards.
It could be a trap.
What was that?
You can put that shit away,
boys. All she needs is a jump.
- Niobe.
- Morpheus.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
We didn't know what happened after....
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
I'm happy to see you too.
- Did you get Neo out?
- Yes.
- How did you know about that?
- The Oracle.
- You saw her?
- Just before the sentinels found us.
- What did she tell you?
- The same thing she always does.
Exactly what I needed to hear.
In 12 hours, the machines
will breach the dock walls.
Every simulation we've run, we've seen
that once the machines are inside...
...the odds of our survival
decrease dramatically.
Thus, our primary objective must be...
...to destroy or disable the diggers
inside the dock.
If we can do that, perhaps we can
prevent them from reaching the city.
If not, the only place we will be able
to mount a defense...
...will be at the entrance of the temple.
It is small and will force
them into a bottleneck...
...allowing us to concentrate
the remainder of our defense.
We understand that you've requested
additional volunteers.
- That is correct.
- Precisely what size force...
...are you planning to commit
to the primary dock objective?
Right now, the entire APU Corps
and half the infantry.
- Half the infantry?
- If it were up to me, councillor...
...I'd take every man, woman and child,
put a gun in their hand...
...and march them into that dock.
Perhaps it is best
that it is not up to you.
Time will tell, councillor.
Commander, just one more question.
Has there been word
from the Nebuchadnezzar?
None, and at this point there's no reason
to expect there will be.
Perhaps.
But we can hope.
I'm afraid hope is an indulgence
I don't have time for.
- Zee, what are you doing?
- Making shells.
They're evacuating our level.
We have to go.
- I'm not going with you.
- What?
They've called for volunteers
to hold the dock.
Kids, you stay here.
I know how you feel,
but you can't do this.
- I have to.
- Why?
Because I love him.
I love him the same as he loves me.
And if I were out there and he
were here, I know what he'd do.
But you're gonna get yourself killed.
It's crazy, Zee.
Maybe it is. But ask yourself,
if it were Dozer...
...and you knew the only chance you had
to see him was to hold the dock...
...what would you do?
Make shells.
What the shit is going on over here?
An accident, sir. I didn't see--
- I'm sorry.
- Who the hell are you?
A unit volunteer, sir.
What's a pod-born pencil-neck like you
doing volunteering for my Corps?
I want to do my part, sir.
We gotta hold the dock.
- How old are you, kid?
- Eighteen.
Should have said 16,
I might have believed that.
Okay, I'm 16.
Minimum age for the Corps is 18.
Sixteen's too young.
The machines don't care how old I am.
They'll kill me just the same.
Ain't that the goddamn truth.
Give me a chance, sir.
I won't let you down.
You do...
...and you'll find me and the machines
have got something in common.
Okay, charge the igniter.
She lives again.
Want us to patch an uplink to reload
the operations software, Sparky?
That'd be swell. Could you clean
the windshield while you're at it?
Uplinks in place.
I'm bringing her back online.
Looking good, except, uh....
Something's wrong
with the Matrix feed.
No, there's not. You're looking
at what we're looking at.
- What's going on in there?
- Whatever it is, it can't be good.
The machines have taken Junction 21.
The way I see it, if we drop down
from broadcast here...
...intersect 153, we might surprise them.
We'll go first, hammer as deep
as we can, then blow our EMP.
Hopefully we can punch a hole
big enough for you to get through.
It ain't pretty, but the way I see it,
it's the only way back.
No, it's not.
There's another way. A support line.
It drops down right here,
1000 meters short of 21.
If we're lucky, we may be able to
slip down without them ever knowing.
That's a mechanical line.
It's impossible.
- No one can pilot mechanical.
- I can.
- Bullshit.
- I've done it.
- That was a long time ago, Niobe.
- I said I can do it.
So what? You'll be the only one that can.
There's no way we can follow you.
Hi.
I know time is always against us.
I'm sorry that I took so long.
- But I wanted to be sure.
- Sure of what?
- I know what I have to do.
- What?
There's no easy way to say this,
so I'll just say it.
- I have to take one of the ships.
- What?
To go where?
To the machine city.
I know it's difficult to understand.
No, it's not. You're out
of your goddamn mind.
I still have to go.
In 100 years, no ship has been
within 100 kilometers of it.
- You'll never make it.
- I have to try.
- Is this what the Oracle has told you?
- No.
This is asinine. If you want
to kill yourself, do it...
...but do it without
wasting our ships.
- You have to believe me. I have to go.
- Bullshit!
I am the captain of this ship.
I say where it has to go!
And this ship will go to hell
long before I let you take it anywhere.
- He can take mine.
- You can't do that.
Don't try to tell me
what I can or cannot do...
...with my ship
after that little speech.
- But for chrissake, Niobe--
- I'll pilot this ship, he can take mine.
If we leave inside the hour,
we'll reach Zion as the machines do.
That's as good a plan as any.
It's a waste. A goddamn waste.
Two ships, two directions.
Sounds like providence,
doesn't it, Morpheus?
- You've never believed in the One.
- I still don't.
Then why are you doing this?
I believe in him.
Thank you.
- What's that for?
- To help you relax.
To make it easier for you to remember.
What if I don't want to remember?
Why would you want that?
What if I blew that EMP?
What if I did destroy those ships...
...and I am responsible
for the deaths of all those men?
If I did that...
...it wouldn't be very safe
for me here, would it?
Of course, it might not be
very safe for you either.
I'm ready.
Trinity...
...there's something I have to say.
Something you need to understand.
I know I'm supposed to go.
But beyond that...
...I don't know. I....
I know. You don't think
you're coming back.
I knew it the moment you said you had
to leave. I could see it in your face.
Just like you knew the moment
you looked at me...
...that I was coming with you.
I'm scared, Trin.
So am I.
It took me 10 minutes
to buckle up one boot.
But I'll tell you something.
Six hours ago, I told the Merovingian...
...I was ready to give anything
and everything for you.
Do you know what's changed
in the last six hours?
No.
Nothing.
- Finished loading ammunition?
- Just about.
Let's move it. We are out of time.
You're not leaving them anything?
He said he didn't need it.
I ain't saying goodbye.
I'm saying good luck.
Thank you.
I can only hope you know
what you're doing.
Me too.
It was an honor, sir.
No, the honor is still mine.
- We're ready, sir.
- About damn time.
We're already late, captain,
so let's hit it and hit it hard.
Bye, baby.
Take good care of them.
Ready?
Engine's still firing.
Must be a fuse. I'll check it out.
I should've known he'd
send his bitch first.
Bane.
No one ever got away from me
as many times as you did.
Every time, I thought it was the last.
Every time, I was sure we had you,
but you'd slip through our fingers.
I really can't express
just how aggravating that can be.
What are you talking about?
I think I might enjoy killing you
as much as killing him.
Neo, it's Bane. He's psychotic!
You're gonna pay for that.
- Twenty-seven kilometers to go.
- We got an emergency.
- What is it, AK?
- It's Maggie, sir.
She's dead, murdered.
I think it was Bane.
Goddamn it.
I knew it. I knew he was
out of his goddamn mind.
He fired that EMP.
Goddamn it, I should have
beaten it out of him.
We searched the whole ship, captain.
He ain't here.
- I know where he is.
- The Logos.
- We gotta go back.
- Too late.
- What if they need our help?
- It's too dangerous.
- Why?
- Because if he's killed them...
...he'll control another EMP.
At this point, they're on their own.
Just like us.
Mr. Anderson.
I see you are as predictable in this world
as you are in the other.
- What?
- He's out of his mind.
It might appear that way.
But Mr. Anderson and I know...
...that appearances can be deceiving.
Confused, Mr. Anderson?
It'll all become clear in a moment.
Thank you for bringing me the gun.
You can set it down there.
Don't do it.
- Shoot. Shoot now.
- Yes, shoot. Fry us. Burn us alive.
Do it. If you don't, he'll kill us both.
Look at him. He knows
he should do it, but he won't.
- He can't.
- Do it.
Back away from the gun
and turn around.
Let her go.
Somehow familiar, isn't it?
We've been here before,
you and I, remember?
I do. I think of nothing else.
- Who are you?
- Still don't recognize me?
I admit, it is difficult to even think
encased in this rotting piece of meat.
The stink of it filling every breath,
a suffocating cloud you can't escape.
Disgusting.
Look at how pathetically fragile it is.
Nothing this weak is meant to survive.
- What do you want?
- I want what you want.
Yes. That's it, Mr. Anderson.
Look past the flesh.
Look through the soft gelatin of these
dull cow eyes and see your enemy.
- No.
- Oh, yes, Mr. Anderson.
- It can't be.
- There's nowhere I can't go.
There is nowhere I won't find you.
- It's impossible.
- Not impossible.
Inevitable.
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
This is it. It's gotta be.
Oh, no.
I wish you could see yourself,
Mr. Anderson.
Blind messiah.
You're a symbol for all of your kind,
Mr. Anderson.
Helpless.
Pathetic.
Just waiting to be put out
of your misery.
I can see you.
It's not over, Mr. Anderson.
It's not over.
- Trinity!
- Neo.
Neo.
Oh, no. Your eyes.
I'll be okay.
It's all right, Trin.
But I think you're gonna have to drive.
Seismic's projecting
22 minutes to breach.
They can't know we don't have an EMP.
They'll have to attack in waves.
Concentrate our offense on the diggers.
Order the APUs into position.
Yes, sir.
Come on, move.
All right!
This is it.
Now, you all know me,
so I'll just say this as simple as I can.
If it's our time to die, it's our time.
All I ask is, if we have
to give these bastards our lives...
...we give them hell before we do!
- Yeah!
- You scared, Charra?
- Shit, yeah.
But I'll make you a deal.
You keep loading, I keep shooting.
Deal.
- Holy Christ, would you look at that.
- Quiet.
- How far to the opening?
- 1.4 kilometers.
- We're still generating too hot a field.
- Ghost, kill all auxiliary systems.
- Full manual. Drop down four pads.
- It'll bottom out.
- Easy, baby.
- Seven hundred meters.
If we can just get close enough....
Six hundred meters.
There.
Shit!
- Jig's up, here they come.
- Give me full power.
Man the gun turrets,
every goddamn one of them. Go!
Ghost, you're the best gunner we have,
go with them. Morpheus, take his place.
I'm coming, baby.
Here they come.
- Slow down, this ain't the Logos.
- Hang on to your lunch, here we go.
Holy Christ, I didn't know
this ship could do that.
Breach! The dock is breached!
Knuckle up!
For Zion!
Shit.
Come on, let's go.
Knuckle up!
Reload!
Reload nine!
Go, go! Move, move!
Watch your left!
Don't let them through!
Zuka!
Oh, my God.
Where the hell's my infantry? I want
that goddamn machine taken down!
Dig this!
Oh, shit!
- Yeah!
- Bogey two at the breach point!
Goddamn it!
Shit, she's got a fat ass.
- Keep them off me!
- Christ, there's a shitstorm of them.
- Captain, you see that?
- They're after the radio. Stop them!
Damn it!
Yeah.
Grab my belt.
Just give me one clean shot.
Damn it!
Charra!
- I got incoming!
- We got a dock full of incoming!
- Yes, sir. But this is different, sir.
- What?
I think it's one of ours, sir.
- That's impossible.
- Holographics are trying to confirm.
Contact them.
I want access codes.
We're trying, sir.
There's no response.
It's a trick. That's not one of ours,
it can't be.
That's a mechanical line.
No one can pilot mechanical.
- Forward aft, 30 degrees at 80 percent.
- Thirty degrees, 80.
- Lower starboard 60 degrees, 20 percent.
- Sixty degrees.
- Shit! Come on, keep up!
- I'm trying!
Sir, holographic confirms.
It's the Hammer, sir.
How can that be?
It's under attack, sustaining damage.
At present velocity,
it'll reach Gate Three in 12 minutes.
Their EMP could take out every sentinel.
It'd take out more than that.
It'll wipe out our defense system.
We blow an EMP inside,
we lose the dock.
Sir, we already lost the dock.
Open the gate.
Gate Three is not responding!
We've taken critical damage, sir!
We've lost control!
We can't open it!
There's the exit.
On my mark, give me full power
90 degrees to lower-left starboard.
Full power...
...ninety degrees.
Now!
Hold on, baby.
Goddamn, woman, you can drive.
We ain't home yet.
What about the gate?
Sentinels are inside the dock.
Are we too late?
- How many APUs are operational?
- Thirteen, sir.
Get me the one closest to Gate Three.
Reload!
He's pissing metal.
Go!
Heads up! They're coming around!
Behind you!
It's jammed!
Forget it, kid! Get out of here!
Got it!
Captain Mifune.
Oh, no.
They're coming.
The Hammer.
What?
You have to open that gate.
Cut the counterweights.
You can do it.
Hurry. There's no time.
Captain...
...I didn't finish the training program.
Neither did I.
- Lock that down!
- Kill the feeder!
We won't make it.
We gotta blow the EMP now.
Come on, someone, please.
Keep the weight forward.
Light as a feather.
Holographic reports Captain Mifune's
APU is up and moving to Gate Three.
Don't over-squeeze the trigger.
Mifune's APU just reached Gate Three.
- How much time?
- Two minutes to impact.
- Captain Mifune, do you copy?
- I think his radio is down, sir.
Mifune...
...this is Lock.
I don't know if you can hear me,
but if you can...
...the Hammer's two minutes away.
You've got two minutes, captain,
to get that gate open.
Link.
Get to the main deck!
Charge the EMP!
Do it, kid.
Neo. I believe.
- Yes!
- Can we make it?
We ain't come this far.
Almost home, almost home.
Burn it, Link!
- You did it.
- No.
We did it.
You're a hell of a pilot.
Some things in this world never change.
But some things do?
Luckily...
...some things do.
Link!
- Zee? Zee!
- Link!
I knew you'd come. I knew it.
I made a promise.
You did wear it.
Are you kidding?
I'm never gonna take it off.
Three captains, one ship.
I'll assume the other ships were lost
under equally pointless circumstances.
Good to see you too, Jason.
The Council's waiting to hear
your explanation.
Forgive me for not attending,
but I have to try to salvage this debacle.
Did I miss something?
I thought we saved the dock.
That's the problem with you people.
You can't think but five minutes
in front of you.
That EMP knocked out almost every
piece of hardware and every APU.
If I were the machines,
I'd send every sentinel here now.
Save the dock, captain?
You handed it to them on a silver platter.
Come on, get it cut.
The bridge is clear.
Do you hear that?
Get that cable run!
- I want the system back online!
- It's the dock. They've got incoming.
Order everyone to fall back.
Seal the shaft. Now.
Move it!
Oh, my God.
- All clear.
- Do it.
- Go! Come on! Run!
- Go!
Your move.
So you gave them your ship?
- That is correct, councillor, I did.
- Knowing what he planned to do with it?
The Oracle said nothing of this?
She told me Neo would need my help,
and I would choose to help him or not.
But what hope can a single vessel have
against their entire defense system?
None. It's completely impossible.
But he wouldn't listen.
He wouldn't even take any ammunition.
He was totally out of his goddamn mind.
No, he wasn't.
Neo is doing what he believes
he must do.
I don't know if what he's doing is right.
I don't know...
...if he'll reach the machine city.
And if he does, I don't know
what he can do to save us.
But I do know that as long as there is
a single breath in his body...
...he will not give up.
And neither can we.
Temperature's dropping.
Here we go.
We're over the fields, aren't we?
How do you know that?
I can feel them.
Over there.
There's our path. Can you see it?
Three lines.
Power lines.
Follow them.
What are they doing?
I don't know.
Lieutenant?
Goddamn it.
What do we do now?
It is now a matter of time.
The machines will breach
the walls of this city.
I recommend that the Council join the
non-military personnel inside the temple.
How long do we have?
Two hours. Maybe less.
My men have fortified the entrance with
enough artillery to make our last stand.
Beyond that, there isn't anything more
I can do.
Commander, do you think that
we have any chance of surviving?
If I were you, I wouldn't
ask me that question.
I would ask him.
- Why?
- He's the one who believes in miracles.
There. Those mountains.
That's it.
- Do you see what's out there?
- Yes.
If you tell me we'll make it,
I'll believe you.
We'll make it.
We have to.
Sentinels.
There's too many!
Gotcha!
- I need help here!
- I can't beat them.
- What do we do?
- Go up, over them.
- What?
- The sky! It's the only way.
Then up we go.
Beautiful.
Pump the igniter. The ship will start.
Again. Slowly.
Now!
Trin?
Trinity?
- I'm here.
- Where?
Here.
We made it.
You said we would.
It's unbelievable, Trin.
Light everywhere.
Like the whole thing was built of light.
I wish you could see what I see.
You've already shown me so much.
What is it, Trinity?
What's wrong?
I can't go with you, Neo.
I've gone as far as I can.
What?
Oh, no.
Oh, no. No, no.
It's all right.
It's time.
I've done all that I could do.
Now you have to do the rest.
You have to finish it.
You have to save Zion.
I can't.
- Not without you.
- Yes, you can.
You will.
I believe it. I always have.
Trinity.
Trinity, you can't die.
You can't.
Yes, I can.
You brought me back once.
But not this time.
Do you remember...
...on that roof, after you caught me...
...the last thing I said to you?
You said, "I'm sorry."
I wish I hadn't.
That was my last thought.
I wished I had one more chance...
...to say what really mattered.
To say how much I loved you.
How grateful I was for every moment
I was with you.
But by the time I knew how to say
what I wanted to, it was too late.
But you brought me back.
You gave me my wish.
One more chance to say
what I really wanted to say.
Kiss me.
Once more...
...kiss me.
Get that ammunition where it belongs!
You got one chance to get this right.
Get that damn thing mounted!
- Hurry.
- Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Neo...
...if you're gonna do something,
do it quick.
I only ask to say
what I've come to say.
After that, do what you want,
and I won't try and stop you.
Speak.
The program Smith has grown
beyond your control.
Soon he will spread through this city
as he spread through the Matrix.
You cannot stop him.
- But I can.
- We don't need you!
We need nothing!
If that's true, then I've made a mistake,
and you should kill me now.
What do you want?
Peace.
What are they doing?
What are you doing?
Morpheus!
And if you fail?
I won't.
Neo.
He fights for us.
Mr. Anderson, welcome back.
We missed you.
You like what I've done with the place?
It ends tonight.
I know it does. I've seen it.
That's why the rest of me
is just going to enjoy the show...
...because we already know
that I'm the one that beats you.
Can you feel it, Mr. Anderson...
...closing in on you?
Oh, I can.
I really should thank you for it.
After all, it was your life...
...that taught me the purpose of all life.
The purpose of life is to end.
Why, Mr. Anderson?
Why, why, why?
Why do you do it?
Why? Why get up?
Why keep fighting?
Do you believe you're fighting
for something?
For more than your survival?
Can you tell me what it is?
Do you even know?
Is it freedom or truth?
Perhaps peace? Could it be for love?
Illusions, Mr. Anderson.
Vagaries of perception.
Temporary constructs
of a feeble human intellect...
...trying desperately
to justify an existence...
...that is without meaning or purpose!
And all of them as artificial
as the Matrix itself...
...although only a human mind could
invent something as insipid as love.
You must be able to see it,
Mr. Anderson.
You must know it by now. You can't
win. It's pointless to keep fighting.
Why, Mr. Anderson, why?
Why do you persist?
Because I choose to.
This is my world! My world!
Wait.
I've seen this.
This is it. This is the end.
Yes. You were laying right there,
just like that.
And I.... I....
I stand here, right here,
and I'm supposed to say something.
I say:
"Everything that has a beginning
has an end, Neo."
What? What did I just say?
No, no. This isn't right.
This can't be right.
Get away from me!
What are you afraid of?
It's a trick.
You were right, Smith.
You were always right.
It was inevitable.
Is it over?
Oh, no, no, no.
No, it's not fair.
It is done.
It doesn't make sense.
He did it.
He saved us.
It's over! He did it! He did it!
He did it! It's over!
- What is it? What happened?
- Sir, he did it, sir. Neo, he did it.
- Did what?
- He ended the war.
The machines, they're gone.
The war is over, sir. The war is over.
Zion! Zion!
Zion, it's over!
It's over!
The war is over!
Whoo!
I have imagined this moment...
...for so long.
Is this real?
Neo, wherever you are...
...thank you.
Good morning.
Well, now. Ain't this a surprise.
You played a very dangerous game.
Change always is.
Just how long do you think
this peace is going to last?
As long as it can.
What about the others?
What others?
The ones that want out.
Obviously, they will be freed.
I have your word?
What do you think I am? Human?
Oracle!
We were afraid we might not find you.
Everything's okay now.
Look, look.
Just look at that.
Beautiful.
Did you do that?
For Neo.
That's nice.
I know he'd love it.
Will we ever see him again?
I suspect so.
Someday.
Did you always know?
Oh, no. No, I didn't.
But I believed.
I believed.
Provided by explosiveskull
(https://twitter.com/kaboomskull)
Modify by Blue-Bird™
Sync & corrections by Blue-Bird™